<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CDN on Council of Elrond</title>
    <link>https://songkou.github.io/tags/cdn/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CDN on Council of Elrond</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 21:29:04 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://songkou.github.io/tags/cdn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Load_Balancing</title>
      <link>https://songkou.github.io/posts/load_balancing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 21:29:04 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://songkou.github.io/posts/load_balancing/</guid>
      <description>LoadBalancing Load balancing (Server Load Balance) means to balance and distribute the load (work tasks) to multiple operating units for execution, so that the entire system can complete the task together.
Load balancing provides a cheap and effective method to expand the bandwidth of network devices and servers, increase throughput, enhance network data processing capabilities, and improve network flexibility and availability. According to the different implementation purposes of load balancing, load balancing can be divided into two types.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CDN_Cache_Cluster_communication</title>
      <link>https://songkou.github.io/posts/cdn_cache_cluster_communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 12:29:04 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://songkou.github.io/posts/cdn_cache_cluster_communication/</guid>
      <description>Cache Cluster Communication The main goal of collaborative interaction within the Cache server cluster is to establish a good communication channel between each server node, communicate in a timely manner about the content cache on the server, and provide users with a good service experience through collaboration between servers in the cluster.
Communication between Cache server clusters can be divided into two categories: loose coupling and tight coupling. Among them, loosely coupled Cache communication protocols based on network messages include: ICP, HTCP, Cache Digest, Cache Pre-filling, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CDN_Notes</title>
      <link>https://songkou.github.io/posts/cdn_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 02:36:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://songkou.github.io/posts/cdn_notes/</guid>
      <description>Content Delivery Network Below is all my personal understandings
Full Name :Content Delivery Network or Content Ddistribute Network Basically, CDN solution solves a common issue: There will always be a bottleneck on the internet, due to different service providers, or geo locations, etc. Which impact the network performance. On the other hand, Latency control is one of the most important indicators nowadays. With CDN, You can deliver a more reliable and stable network by putting certain Servers in certain places in the internet, and building a intelligent network on top of the internet.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
