<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Operating System on Council of Elrond</title>
    <link>https://songkou.github.io/categories/operating-system/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Operating System on Council of Elrond</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 18:33:58 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://songkou.github.io/categories/operating-system/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mysql_installation</title>
      <link>https://songkou.github.io/posts/mysql_installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 18:33:58 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://songkou.github.io/posts/mysql_installation/</guid>
      <description>The general view of the difference between mysql and marinaDB can refer to this link:
https://blog.panoply.io/a-comparative-vmariadb-vs-mysql
And I quote some here:
MySQL: MySQL is an open-source relational database management system (RDBMS). Just like all other relational databases, MySQL uses tables, constraints, triggers, roles, stored procedures and views as the core components that you work with. A table consists of rows, and each row contains a same set of columns. MySQL uses primary keys to uniquely identify each row (a.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux_name_space</title>
      <link>https://songkou.github.io/posts/linux_name_space/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 14:52:01 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://songkou.github.io/posts/linux_name_space/</guid>
      <description>Linux NameSpace Docker denpends on Linux NameSpace, Thus this is a brief explaination on linux name space.
We can use unshare command to manipulate/playaround with linux name spaces.
How to check what kind of linux namespace is supported We can use “man unshare” to check what kind of linux namespace is supported. There are 8 types of name spaces:
mount namespace Mounting and unmounting filesystems will not affect the rest of the system (CLONE_NEWNS flag), except for filesystems which are explicitly marked as shared (with mount --make-shared; see /proc/self/mountinfo or findmnt -o+PROPAGATION for the shared flags).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
